Lloyd E. Cotsen collection of Potter Family photographs,1865-1935: Finding Aid
Cotsen Children's Library
- Landscapes, 1880 May-1913 September; 1021 items
  - Photograph of Bertram Potter painting: riverbend, boulder in foreground, circa 1904 April; 1285; 1 item 12.2 x 16.2 cm.
    Cataloger supplied title. No inscription. Rupert Potter's inscription on two of the photographs in this group, absent any other marks of authorship, suggests the possibility that he made all of the photographs of Bertrams paintings. Similarity in style and printing suggests this photo may have been made at same time as CTSN Potter 1281, dated Apr 1904. No external evidence is available to confirm this. Printed from same negative as CTSN Potter 1286.
  - Photograph of Bertram Potter painting: riverbend, boulder in foreground, circa 1904 April; 1286; 1 item 12.0 x 15.9 cm.
    Cataloger supplied title. No inscription. Rupert Potter's inscription on two of the photographs in this group, absent any other marks of authorship, suggests the possibility that he made all of the photographs of Bertrams paintings. Similarity in style and printing suggests this photo may have been made at same time as CTSN Potter 1281, dated Apr 1904. No external evidence is available to confirm this. Printed from same negative as CTSN Potter 1285.
  - Photograph of Bertram Potter painting: stand of trees on a fell top, circa 1904 April; 1287; 1 item 11.1 x 15.0 cm.
  - Photograph of Bertram Potter painting: winter landscape with sheep, circa 1904 April; 1288; 1 item 12.0 x 16.2 cm.
    Cataloger supplied title. No inscription. Rupert Potter's inscription on two of the photographs in this group, absent any other marks of authorship, suggests the possibility that he made all of the photographs of Bertrams paintings. Similarity in style and printing suggests this photo may have been made at same time as CTSN Potter 1281, dated Apr 1904. No external evidence is available to confirm this. Printed from same negative as CTSN Potter 1289.
  - Photograph of Bertram Potter painting: winter landscape with sheep, circa 1904 April; 1289; 1 item 12.0 x 16.2 cm.
    Cataloger supplied title. No inscription. Rupert Potter's inscription on two of the photographs in this group, absent any other marks of authorship, suggests the possibility that he made all of the photographs of Bertrams paintings. Similarity in style and printing suggests this photo may have been made at same time as CTSN Potter 1281, dated Apr 1904. No external evidence is available to confirm this. Printed from same negative as CTSN Potter 1288.
  - Photograph of Bertram Potter painting: landscape with cottages, circa 1904 April; 1290; 1 item 10.7 x 15.1 cm.
    Cataloger supplied title. No inscription. Rupert Potter's inscription on two of the photographs in this group, absent any other marks of authorship, suggests the possibility that he made all of the photographs of Bertrams paintings. Similarity in style and printing suggests this photo may have been made at same time as CTSN Potter 1281, dated Apr 1904. No external evidence is available to confirm this. Printed from same negative as CTSN Potter 1291.
  - Photograph of Bertram Potter painting: landscape with cottages, circa 1904 April; 1291; 1 item 12.1 x 16.5 cm.
  - Photograph of Bertram Potter painting: valley landscape with birds flying, circa 1904 April; 1292; 1 item 10.0 x 15.2 cm.
    Cataloger supplied title. No inscription. Rupert Potter's inscription on two of the photographs in this group, absent any other marks of authorship, suggests the possibility that he made all of the photographs of Bertrams paintings. Possibly made at same time as CTSN Potter 1281, dated Apr 1904; though printed on a different paper, film format and setting appear the same. No external evidence is available to confirm this. Printed from same negative as CTSN Potter 1293.
  - Photograph of Bertram Potter painting: valley landscape with birds flying, circa 1904 April; 1293; 1 item 11.9 x 16.3 cm.
    Cataloger supplied title. No inscription. Rupert Potter's inscription on two of the photographs in this group, absent any other marks of authorship, suggests the possibility that he made all of the photographs of Bertrams paintings. Possibly made at same time as CTSN Potter 1281, dated Apr 1904; though printed on a different paper, film format and setting appear the same. No external evidence is available to confirm this. Printed from same negative as CTSN Potter 1292.
  - Photograph of Bertram Potter painting: landscape with peat mounds, circa 1904 April; 1294; 1 item 11.9 x 16.3 cm.
    Cataloger supplied title. No inscription. Rupert Potter's inscription on two of the photographs in this group, absent any other marks of authorship, suggests the possibility that he made all of the photographs of Bertrams paintings. Possibly made at same time as CTSN Potter 1281, dated Apr 1904; though printed on a different paper, film format and setting appear the same. No external evidence is available to confirm this.
  - Photograph of Bertram Potter painting: tilled field with buildings in the distance, circa 1904 April; 1295; 1 item 11.9 x 16.3 cm.
    Cataloger supplied title. No inscription. Presumably by Rupert Potter. Rupert Potter's inscription on two of the photographs in this group, absent any other marks of authorship, suggests the possibility that he made all of the photographs of Bertrams paintings. Possibly made at same time as CTSN Potter 1281, dated Apr 1904; though printed on a different paper, film format and setting appear the same. No external evidence is available to confirm this. Torn.
  - Photograph of Bertram Potter painting: winter landscape with brush, stone wall, and distant cottages, circa 1904 April; 1296; 1 item 11.9 x 16.3 cm.
    Cataloger supplied title. No inscription. Presumably by Rupert Potter. Rupert Potter's inscription on two of the photographs in this group, absent any other marks of authorship, suggests the possibility that he made all of the photographs of Bertrams paintings. Possibly made at same time as CTSN Potter 1281, dated Apr 1904; though printed on a different paper, film format and setting appear the same. No external evidence is available to confirm this.
  - Photograph of Bertram Potter painting: wide river, circa 1904 April; 1297; 1 item 11.9 x 16.5 cm.
    Cataloger supplied title. No inscription. Presumably by Rupert Potter. Rupert Potter's inscription on two of the photographs in this group, absent any other marks of authorship, suggests the possibility that he made all of the photographs of Bertrams paintings. Possibly made at same time as CTSN Potter 1281, dated Apr 1904; though printed on a different paper, film format and setting appear the same. No external evidence is available to confirm this. Printed from same negative as CTSN Potter 1298-9.
- Bertram Potter paintings, 1895 September-1935 September 25; 10 items
  The third and final series consists of eight photographs of paintings by Bertram Potter and two receipts from photographer John Heelis to Beatrix.
  The eight photographs of Bertram's paintings are followed by the Heelis receipts.
  - Photograph of Bertram Potter painting: wide river, circa 1904 April; 1298; 1 item 12.0 x 16.2 cm.
    Cataloger supplied title. No inscription. Presumably by Rupert Potter. Rupert Potter's inscription on two of the photographs in this group, absent any other marks of authorship, suggests the possibility that he made all of the photographs of Bertrams paintings. Possibly made at same time as CTSN Potter 1281, dated Apr 1904; though printed on a different paper, film format and setting appear the same. No external evidence is available to confirm this. Printed from same negative as CTSN Potter 1297, 1299.
  - Photograph of Bertram Potter painting: wide river, circa 1904 April; 1299; 1 item 12.0 x 16.2 cm.
  - Photograph of Bertram Potter painting:stream emerging from a forest, circa 1904 April; 1300; 1 item 12.0 x 16.3 cm.
    Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in ink, unknown hand: at Hill Top Farm./ July 1948. Rupert Potter's inscription on two of the photographs in this group, absent any other marks of authorship, suggests the possibility that he made all of the photographs of Bertrams paintings. Possibly made at same time as CTSN Potter 1281, dated Apr 1904; though printed on a different paper, film format and setting appear the same. No external evidence is available to confirm this. Ink inscription of 1948 relates to the location of the paintings at that date, not to the date or location at which photographs were made.
  - Photograph of Bertram Potter painting: old man and dog seated by a curving path, circa 1904 April; 1301; 1 item 16.5 x 11.9 cm.
  - Photograph of Bertram Potter painting: woman standing by a curving path or stream, circa 1904 April; 1302; 1 item 16.5 x 11.9 cm.
    Cataloger supplied title. No inscription. Presumably by Rupert Potter. Rupert Potter's inscription on two of the photographs in this group, absent any other marks of authorship, suggests the possibility that he made all of the photographs of Bertrams paintings. Possibly made at same time as CTSN Potter 1281, dated Apr 1904; though printed on a different paper, film format and setting appear the same. No external evidence is available to confirm this. Printed from same negative as CTSN Potter 1303.
  - Photograph of Bertram Potter painting: woman standing by a curving path or stream, circa 1904 April; 1303; 1 item 16.2 x 12.0 cm.
    Cataloger supplied title. No inscription. Presumably by Rupert Potter. Rupert Potter's inscription on two of the photographs in this group, absent any other marks of authorship, suggests the possibility that he made all of the photographs of Bertrams paintings. Possibly made at same time as CTSN Potter 1281, dated Apr 1904; though printed on a different paper, film format and setting appear the same. No external evidence is available to confirm this. Printed from same negative as CTSN Potter 1302.
  - Photograph of Bertram Potter painting: boggy landscape, 1895 September; 1304; 1 item 15.9 x 21.0 cm.
    Cataloger supplied title. Inscribed in pencil by Rupert Potter: Sep 1895 / W.
  - Photograph of Bertram Potter painting: lake seen through trees, circa 1904 April; 1305; 1 item 11.4 x 15.8 cm, mounted to 15.9 x 21.2 cm. board
    Cataloger supplied title. No inscription. Presumably by Rupert Potter. Rupert Potter's inscription on two of the photographs in this group, absent any other marks of authorship, suggests the possibility that he made all of the photographs of Bertrams paintings. Similarity in style and printing suggests this photo may have been made at same time as CTSN Potter 1281, dated Apr 1904. No external evidence is available to confirm this.
  - Receipt from John James for payment received from Mrs. H.B. Heelis, 1935 September 25; 1306; 1 item 22.1 x 14.3 cm.
    Receipt from photographer John Jameson for 2 mounted 8x10 enlargements, 2 mounted 8x6 enlargements, 18 postcards, and postage. Sent from Penrith to Beatrix Potter at Castle Cottage, Ambleside. Subject of photographs not known, but probably livestock.
  - Receipt from John James for payment received from Mrs. H.B. Heelis, 1935 September 25; 1307; 1 item 22.1 x 14.3 cm.
- COTSEN5_n1 (Box 1)
- COTSEN5_n2 (Box 2)
- COTSEN5_n3 (Box 3)
- COTSEN5_n4 (Box 4)
- COTSEN5_n5 (Box 5)
- COTSEN5_n6 (Box 6)
- COTSEN5_n7 (Box 7)
- COTSEN5_n8 (Box 8)
- COTSEN5_n9 (Box 9)
- COTSEN5_n10 (Box 10)
- COTSEN5_n11 (Box 11)
- COTSEN5_n12 (Box 12)
- COTSEN5_n13 (Box 13)
- COTSEN5_n14 (Box 14)
- COTSEN5_n15 (Box 15)
- COTSEN5_n16 (Box 16)
- COTSEN5_n17 (Box 17)
- COTSEN5_n18 (Box 18)
- COTSEN5_n19 (Box 19)